classmates
급우
Today we have a special expert here
오늘은 특별한 전문가를 모셨습니다
Come and give a lecture to everyone
와서 모두에게 강의를 해주세요.
Everyone is welcome
모두 환영합니다
Hello students
안녕하세요 학생 여러분
before class
수업 전
I want to ask you a question first
먼저 질문하고 싶습니다.
revolution
혁명
What exactly do you rely on?
당신은 정확히 무엇을 의지합니까?
Many students may say
많은 학생들이 이렇게 말할 수도 있습니다.
Rely on faith
믿음에 의지하라
Relying on the barrel of a gun
총구에 의지해
These are all correct
이것들은 모두 정확합니다
But I want to tell you today
하지만 오늘은 꼭 말해주고 싶어
crucial point
결정적인 포인트
That's the economy
그게 경제야
no financial support
재정적 지원 없음
No money
돈이 없다
There are many things you can't do
할 수 없는 일이 많아요
Where does that money come from?
그 돈은 어디서 나오나요?
development finance
개발 금융
Many students will ask again
많은 학생들이 다시 묻습니다.
So what is finance?
그렇다면 금융이란 무엇인가?
today
오늘
Let's start with this one
이것부터 시작하자
Talking about the silver coins circulating in the base area
거점 지역에 유통되는 은화에 대해 이야기하기
Hello
안녕하세요
Come out for a moment
잠깐만 나오세요
to Baliqiao Road
발리차오 로드 방향
There is a Huiqing teahouse
Huiqing 찻집이 있습니다
I'm here waiting for you
나 여기에서 너를 기다리고있어
fast
빠른
Is there a problem
문제가 있습니까
You'll know when you come
와보면 알게 될 거야
Remember
기억하다
Don't let Zhao An's people see you
Zhao An의 사람들이 당신을 보지 못하게하십시오
Zhao An
자오안
Why is he causing trouble for me again?
그 사람이 왜 또 나한테 말썽을 피우는 걸까?
Anyway, you remember
아무튼 기억나시죠
Don't let Zhao An's people see you
Zhao An의 사람들이 당신을 보지 못하게하십시오
good
좋은
See you soon
곧 봐요
See you or leave
만나거나 떠나거나
Hello
안녕하세요
Guoguo
궈궈
I have to go out later
나중에 나가야 해
Didn’t you say you wanted to buy stationery?
문구류를 사고 싶다고 하지 않았나요?
I'll take you along the way
내가 당신을 길로 데려갈게요
good
좋은
Then we'll see you in the parking lot.
그럼 주차장에서 뵙겠습니다.
hurry up
서둘러요
Why is Chen Shugan following us?
Chen Shugan이 우리를 따르는 이유는 무엇입니까?
Catch me
날 잡아
Catch you
당신을 잡아
Jiang Zhaoguo was probably captured by the Japanese
장자오궈(Jiang Zhaoguo)는 아마도 일본군에 의해 포로로 잡혔을 것이다.
And maybe betrayed me
그리고 어쩌면 나를 배신했을지도 몰라
how do you know
어떻게 알아?
This morning Luo Guanqun and Zhao An
오늘 아침 Luo Guanqun과 Zhao An
Was called to the Military Police Headquarters
헌병사령부로 호출됨
I think Uchida must have given them instructions.
내 생각엔 우치다가 그들에게 지시를 내린 게 틀림없다고 생각한다.
Order to arrest me
나를 체포하라는 명령
I didn’t expect Director Jiang to be that kind of person
장 감독이 그런 사람일 줄은 몰랐다
betrayed me
나를 배신했다
On the one hand, it's to protect you
한편으로는 당신을 보호하기 위해서죠
on the other hand
반면에
You can borrow the help of the Japanese to kill me
나를 죽이려면 일본인의 도움을 빌릴 수 있습니다.
In this case
이 경우
I'll run with you
너와 함께 달려갈게
I call you out
나는 당신을 불러
Not running away with me
나랑 도망치지 않아
Running away won't solve any problems
도망가도 문제는 해결되지 않아
On the contrary, it is Luo Guanqun, the old fox
그와는 반대로 늙은 여우 나관춘이다.
Better skills
더 나은 기술
To lure me out on purpose
일부러 나를 유인하려고
In order to prevent you from falling into Zhao An's hands, he
당신이 조안의 손에 넘어가는 것을 막기 위해 그는
Then I will give him Lao Luo some face.
그러면 라오루오에게 얼굴을 좀 보여주겠습니다.
Just leave me to him
날 그 사람에게 맡겨만 줘
Is there no other way?
다른 방법은 없나요?
What should I do?
어떻게 해야 하나요?
I watched you being arrested
나는 당신이 체포되는 것을 지켜보았습니다
Guoguo
궈궈
Maybe only you can save me
어쩌면 너만이 나를 구할 수 있을지도 몰라
How can I save you?
어떻게 하면 당신을 구할 수 있나요?
I haven't thought of it yet
아직 생각은 안 해봤는데
You go on as usual now
넌 이제 평소대로 가네
Go buy your stationery
가서 문구류를 사세요
What if
만약
in case they
만약에 그들이
What if I kill you?
내가 당신을 죽이면 어떻게 되나요?
I thought about it
나는 그것에 대해 생각했다
Jiang Zhaoguo can be because
Jiang Zhaoguo는 그럴 수 있습니다.
Hanlu and I got too close
한루와 나는 너무 가까워졌다
Although this reason is somewhat far-fetched
이 이유는 다소 억지스럽기는 하지만
But until they have no conclusive evidence
하지만 결정적인 증거가 없을 때까지
I can resist for a while
잠시 저항할 수 있어
I can not do it
나는 그것을 할 수 없습니다
You can do it
할 수 있어요
believe in yourself
자신을 믿으세요
Wait until this happens
이런 일이 일어날 때까지 기다리세요
You promised me
넌 나에게 약속했었다
Must continue
계속해야 함
Being a waste of time
시간낭비인줄
Peacefully
평화롭게
Hang around forever
영원히 머물다
No matter if I am a waste or not
내가 쓰레기든 아니든 상관없어
I will be safe and sound
나는 안전하고 건강할 것이다
Get off quickly
빨리 내리세요
Pick me up in person, Lao Luo
직접 데리러 오세요, Lao Luo
You have to go with me to the Gendarmerie Headquarters
나랑 같이 헌병대 본부로 가야 해
Promotion or salary increase?
승진인가, 급여인상인가?
You'll know when you go there
거기 가보면 알게 될 거야
I really can't help you this time
이번엔 정말 도와줄 수가 없어
Is Manager Luo back?
루오 감독님 돌아오셨나요?
No
아니요
The cars are parked downstairs
차들은 아래층에 주차되어 있어요
He said he hadn't come back yet
아직 돌아오지 않았다고 하더군요
this
이것
Really not back
정말 안 돌아왔어
No one inside
안에는 아무도 없어
Miss Zuo
미스 주오
Manager Luo
루오 매니저
Why are you hiding from me?
왜 나한테 숨어 있는 거야?
large spoon
큰 숟가락
are you blind
너 눈이 멀었니?
Don't I know I'm here?
내가 여기 있는 걸 모르겠나요?
Didn't pay attention just now
지금은 주의를 기울이지 않았습니다
Are you looking for me
나를 찾고 있나요?
I heard that you arrested Chen Jiaping with your own hands
당신이 직접 천자핑(Chen Jiaping)을 체포했다고 들었습니다.
yes
예
Follow orders
주문 따르기
I have no way
난 방법이 없어
Heart-wrenching
가슴 아프게
At least you should say something for him
적어도 그 사람한테는 한마디라도 해줘야지
Is it right
맞아
Miss Zuo
미스 주오
You don't know
당신은 모른다
Our manager Luo
우리 매니저 루오
This talk is almost broken.
이 얘기는 거의 깨졌습니다.
no way
안 돼요
Because the Japanese have evidence
일본인은 증거가 있기 때문에
what evidence
어떤 증거
Hurry up and get some tea
빨리 가서 차 좀 마셔
You should have heard about it
당신은 그것에 대해 들었어야 했어요
Yesterday's military reunification agent
어제의 군통일요원
Sneak attack on Japanese military uniform factory
일본 군복공장 몰래 습격
The leader was sent from Chongqing
지도자는 충칭에서 파견되었다.
The official position is not small
공식 입장도 적지 않아
A labor certificate was found on him
그에게서 노동 증명서가 발견되었습니다
Said it was given by Chen Jiaping
Chen Jiaping이 제공했다고 합니다.
Taihe Trading Company has a labor certificate in hand
Taihe Trading Company는 노동 증명서를 보유하고 있습니다.
Only Zhao An
오직 자오안(Zhao An)
yes
예
Then maybe Chen Jiaping stole it
그렇다면 Chen Jiaping이 그것을 훔쳤을 수도 있습니다.
unimportant
중요하지 않은
The focus is on oral confession
구두 고백에 초점이 맞춰져 있다
People said
사람들은 말했다
The one who colluded was Chen Jiaping
공모한 사람은 천자핑(Chen Jiaping)이었다.
Didn’t mention Zhao An
자오안(Zhao An)을 언급하지 않았나요?
You believe it
당신은 그것을 믿습니다
The Japanese believed it
일본인들은 그것을 믿었다
The Gendarmerie Headquarters came to our house and searched it all over.
헌병사령부가 우리 집에 찾아와서 여기저기 수색을 하더군요.
Chen Jiaping's office
천자핑의 사무실
Also turned upside down
또한 거꾸로 뒤집힌
There is no evidence of collusion with Chongqing.
충칭과 공모했다는 증거는 없다.
Just a confession
그냥 고백이에요
Why do you arrest him?
왜 그를 체포합니까?
Miss Zuo
미스 주오
drink tea
차를 마시다
Calm down your anger
분노를 진정시키세요
Japanese
일본어
Don't call it a confession.
그것을 고백이라고 부르지 마십시오.
Just a look
그냥 보세요
He can also be convicted immediately
즉시 유죄판결을 받을 수도 있다
And now
그리고 지금
This is not only
이뿐만 아니라
It's about this labor certificate.
이 노동 증명서에 관한 것입니다.
The Japanese say they have this information
일본인들은 이 정보를 가지고 있다고 말합니다.
There is a military spy codenamed Five of Hearts
코드네임 Five of Hearts라는 군 스파이가 있습니다.
Just lurking in our business
우리 사업에 숨어있을 뿐이야
Now the Japanese suspect Chen Jiaping
이제 일본인 용의자 천자핑(Chen Jiaping)
It's the five of hearts
하트 5개야
This is simply impossible
이것은 단순히 불가능합니다
I don’t think it’s possible either.
나는 그것이 가능하다고 생각하지 않는다.
Just found a four of clubs
방금 클럽 4개를 찾았어요
Now comes another Five of Hearts
이제 또 다른 Five of Hearts가 옵니다
Otherwise
그렇지 않으면
Call them all
그들 모두에게 전화하세요
Come play poker at my place
우리집으로 와서 포커나 해라
Endless
끝없는
Manager Luo
루오 매니저
Chen Jiaping has been following you for so long
Chen Jiaping은 오랫동안 당신을 따라왔습니다.
This business is up and down
이 사업은 위아래로 움직인다
Everyone knows that he is your Manager Luo’s man
그 사람이 루오 매니저의 남자인 건 다들 아시죠?
Have you never thought about it?
그것에 대해 생각해 본 적이 없나요?
Could it be that someone wanted to frame Chen Jiaping first?
누군가 Chen Jiaping을 먼저 모함하고 싶었을까요?
Drag you into the water again
널 다시 물 속으로 끌고 들어가
I have a breeze on my sleeves
소매에 바람이 불어요
No one can drag me down
누구도 나를 끌어내릴 수 없어
Then you just don't want to save me.
그럼 당신은 나를 구하고 싶지 않은 것뿐입니다.
Zuo Shuangtao
주오솽타오
I feel the same as you
나도 너와 같은 기분이야
I'm always worried about Jia Ping's safety.
저는 항상 Jia Ping의 안전이 걱정됩니다.
Manager Luo
루오 매니저
I can only ask you now
이제 너한테만 물어볼 수 있어
Let me beg you
부탁 좀 할게요
Please save Chen Jiaping
천자핑(Chen Jiaping)을 구해주세요
Manager Luo
루오 매니저
There will be a dinner party later
나중에 저녁 파티가 있을 거예요
OK OK OK
오케이 오케이 오케이
Miss Zuo Shuangtao
미스 주오 솽타오
do not worry
걱정 하지마
Where the Japanese are
일본인이 있는 곳
I will definitely go and beg for mercy again
꼭 가서 또 자비를 빌겠습니다
Where are you?
어디세요?
Also think of a way
방법도 생각해 보세요
We work together
우리는 같이 일한다
Strive to restore Jiaping's innocence
Jiaping의 결백을 회복하기 위해 노력하십시오
Send, send, send
보내다, 보내다, 보내다
Miss Zuo, walk slowly
미스 주오, 천천히 걸어요
don't worry
괜찮아요
Let's think of a solution together
해결책을 함께 생각해 봅시다
Want to exonerate Chen Jiaping
Chen Jiaping을 면죄하고 싶습니다
the only way
유일한 방법
To find someone to blame
비난할 사람을 찾으려면
Since Zhao An became a lackey of the Japanese,
조안(趙冰)이 일본의 하수인이 된 이후,
I don’t know how many patriots have been killed
얼마나 많은 애국자들이 희생되었는지 모르겠습니다
The crime is heinous
범죄가 극악하다
A worthy death
가치 있는 죽음
Another point is
또 다른 점은
Zhao An has repeatedly suspected my identity
자오안은 내 정체를 계속해서 의심해왔다
Don't get rid of him
그를 제거하지 마십시오
I'm in a business
나는 사업을 하고 있어요
It's always at stake
항상 위태로워요
Put the blame on Zhao An
자오안을 비난하라
I can't do it alone
혼자서는 할 수 없어
We must find a way to bring Luo Guanqun into the group.
우리는 Luo Guanqun을 그룹에 합류시킬 방법을 찾아야 합니다.
Our batch
우리 배치
It has been sent from Wuxi
우시에서 보내왔습니다
I'll be in Shanghai in the next two days
저는 앞으로 이틀 안에 상하이에 있을 거예요
After the goods arrive, put them in the warehouse
상품 도착 후 창고에 넣어두세요
don't move for now
지금은 움직이지 마세요
Why
왜
Now is the time to sell at a high price
이제는 고가에 팔아야 할 때다.
Kimura is dead now
기무라는 이제 죽었어
You don't know the gendarmerie
넌 헌병대를 모르지?
Will it cause trouble next?
다음에 문제가 생길까요?
You must act cautiously at this time
이때는 신중하게 행동해야 합니다
Where are the smuggled materials hidden?
밀수품은 어디에 숨겨져 있나요?
How can we rob this batch of smuggled materials?
이 밀수품을 어떻게 훔칠 수 있습니까?
How to get this batch of smuggled materials into Zhao An's hands
이 밀수된 자재 덩어리를 조안의 손에 넘겨주는 방법
Waiting for Luo Guanqun to take the bait
Luo Guanqun이 미끼를 잡기를 기다리고 있습니다.
Yeah
응
There is such a batch of cotton yarn
이런 면사가 있어요
Gave it to Manager Luo
루오 매니저에게 줬어요
double peach
더블 복숭아
Why do you suddenly ask about this?
갑자기 이걸 왜 물어보나요?
Aunt, you don’t know
이모님, 모르시나요??
Something happened to Jia Ping
Jia Ping에게 무슨 일이 일어났나요?
Someone framed him for secretly communicating with Chongqing
누군가가 그를 충칭과 비밀리에 소통했다는 이유로 모함했습니다.
The gendarmerie headquarters arrested him
헌병대 본부가 그를 체포했습니다
dying
사망
How could something like this happen?
어떻게 이런 일이 일어날 수 있습니까?
That's why I came to inquire about it
그래서 그것에 대해 문의하러 왔습니다.
Between uncle and manager Luo
삼촌과 매니저 루오 사이
Do you have any business dealings?
사업상 거래가 있나요?
Then I'll ask Manager Luo to intercede for Jiaping.
그러면 루오 매니저에게 자핑을 위해 중재해 달라고 부탁하겠습니다.
I also have some confidence in my heart.
마음에도 어느 정도 자신감이 생겼습니다.
double peach
더블 복숭아
Just go to Manager Luo and ask for this.
Luo 매니저에게 가서 물어보세요.
If he doesn't want to help
그 사람이 도와주고 싶지 않다면
I asked your uncle to find him
네 삼촌한테 찾아달라고 했어
It's better not to let uncle know
삼촌한테는 알리지 않는 게 좋을 거야
Why
왜
His identity
그의 정체성
If I don’t come forward, I’ll feel uncomfortable
내가 나서지 않으면 불편할 것 같아
Come forward and offend the Japanese again
앞으로 나와 또 일본놈들을 화나게 해라
Just don't make it difficult for him
그 사람을 힘들게 하지 마세요.
I'll go to Manager Luo to beg for mercy.
루오 매니저에게 가서 자비를 구하겠습니다.
If you take some time off, you should be fine.
잠시 쉬면 괜찮을 것 같아요.
double peach
더블 복숭아
You are really becoming more and more sensible
너 진짜 점점 현명해지고 있어
Do not worry
걱정 하지마
Jia Ping will be fine
지아핑은 괜찮을 거야
Look at you, you’ve lost weight
봐봐 살이 빠졌어
latté
웃다??
with added sugar
설탕을 첨가한
Thanks
감사해요
how's it going
어떻게되고 있습니까
this radio station
이 라디오 방송국
I helped Luo Guanqun build it before.
나는 이전에 Luo Guanqun이 그것을 만드는 것을 도왔습니다.
The frequency is one one six seven one
빈도는 하나 하나 여섯 일곱 하나
So I found it quickly
그래서 빨리 찾았어요
The number of the winning horse every day
매일 승리한 말의 수
right
오른쪽
this number
이 번호
Corresponding to these English letters
이 영어 글자에 해당하는
Just find this
이것만 찾아보세요
The message was easily solved
메시지가 쉽게 해결되었습니다.
What you gave me
당신이 나에게 준 것
All done
모두 완료
last night
지난 밤
I called some brothers
나는 몇몇 형제들에게 전화를 걸었다.
Raid No. 9 berth of Puxi Pier
푸시 부두 9번 정박 습격
That's a small cargo ship
저건 작은 화물선이에요
The defense is quite lax
수비가 상당히 허술하다
It didn't take much effort to get it.
그것을 얻는 데는 많은 노력이 필요하지 않았습니다.
Then we took over the boat
그런 다음 우리는 보트를 인수했습니다.
The dozens of boxes of goods that were snatched overnight
하룻밤 사이에 빼앗긴 물건 수십 상자
Shipped
배송됨
Eastbound warehouse
동쪽 창고
this
이것
This is the cotton yarn in that batch of goods
이것은 해당 제품 배치에 포함된 면사입니다.
right
오른쪽
It's this kind of cotton yarn
이런 면실이에요
This kind of 26-count medium-count yarn
이런 종류의 26수 중수사
Only Shanghai can produce
상하이에서만 생산 가능
Japan discovered this year
올해 일본이 발견
There is such cotton yarn being sold in Kuomintang District
국민당에서 이런 면사가 팔리고 있어요
I thought it was smuggled in from Shanghai.
상하이에서 밀수입한 줄 알았어요.
Currently under investigation
현재 조사중
That is to say
즉 말하자면
There is hope to save Chen Jiaping
Chen Jiaping을 구할 희망이 있습니다
I can't say there's hope yet
아직은 희망이 있다고는 말할 수 없어
But things
하지만 것들
It's starting to develop the way we expected.
우리가 예상한 대로 발전하기 시작했습니다.
good
좋은
That's OK
괜찮아
it's okay no problem
괜찮아 문제 없어
don't worry
괜찮아요
Mrs. Chen
첸 부인
Already followed your instructions
이미 귀하의 지시를 따랐습니다.
I pretended to discover it by accident
우연히 발견한 척 했어
The batch of cotton yarn from the eastbound warehouse
동쪽으로 향하는 창고에서 나온 면사 한 묶음
And promptly reported to Captain Zhao
그리고 즉시 자오 선장에게 보고했습니다.
How did he say
그가 어떻게 말했나요?
The eastbound warehouse is Captain Zhao’s territory, right?
동쪽 창고는 자오 선장의 영역이겠죠?
Cotton yarn is in hot demand again
면사의 수요가 다시 뜨겁습니다
This meat reaches the mouth
이 고기가 입에 닿는다
Of course he did his part.
물론 그는 자신의 역할을 다했습니다.
Does he know whose goods it is?
그는 그것이 누구의 물건인지 알고 있나요?
Damasao has been searching the black market for the past two days and asked questions.
다마사오는 지난 이틀간 암시장을 뒤지며 질문을 했습니다.
Captain Zhao has heard about it
자오 선장은 그것에 대해 들었습니다
He suspected that it was Luo Guanqun's goods.
그는 그것이 Luo Guanqun의 물건이라고 의심했습니다.
You took all the goods away
물건을 다 가져가셨어요
Of course
물론
Did he become suspicious?
그 사람이 의심스러워졌나요?
Why are Luo Guanqun’s goods
Luo Guanqun의 상품은 무엇입니까?
Will appear in the warehouse on his property
그의 소유지 창고에 나타날 것입니다
I heard that a ship sank at Puxi Pier
푸시 부두에서 배가 침몰했다는 소식을 들었습니다
Captain Zhao speculated that it was Manager Luo’s boat.
Zhao 선장은 그것이 Luo 매니저의 보트라고 추측했습니다.
He doesn't have time to put his goods away at the moment
그는 지금은 물건을 치울 시간이 없습니다
Just leave it there for a few days
그냥 며칠 동안 그대로 놔두세요
Well done
잘하셨어요
Have you found the whereabouts of the cotton yarn?
면사의 행방을 찾으셨나요?
Do you know where this batch of cotton yarn is shipped?
이 면사 묶음이 어디로 배송되는지 아시나요?
Lin'an
린안
There's a trading point over there
저기 거래처가 있어요
Now the Japanese are investigating
지금 일본이 조사중
Transporting smuggled goods into the country
밀수품을 국내로 운송하는 행위
Including Hubei and Zhebei
후베이성, 저베이성 포함
Clues have been found
단서가 발견되었습니다
It's cotton yarn
면사예요
If this matter is known to the Japanese
이 일이 일본인에게 알려지면
Can't keep position
자리를 지킬 수 없다
I can't even save my head
머리도 못 구해
The robber stole the cotton yarn
강도가 면사를 훔쳤어요
I think at most it is
내 생각엔 기껏해야 그럴 것 같아
Get it on the black market and exchange it for money
암시장에 가서 돈으로 교환하세요
The Japanese may not know that, right?
일본 사람들은 그걸 모를 수도 있겠죠?
hope so
그러길 바라
So be sure to remember
그러니 꼭 기억하세요
Whose is this batch of goods?
이 물품 묶음은 누구의 것입니까?
must find
찾아야 한다
It doesn't matter if you can't find it back
다시 못찾아도 상관없어
Don't let the Japanese know
일본인들에게 알리지 마세요
yes
예
OK
좋아요
I will try my best to check it out again.
다시한번 확인해보도록 노력하겠습니다.
Did you hear it right?
들은 게 맞나요?
I heard clearly
분명히 들었어
Erduidao said it himself
Erduidao가 직접 말했습니다.
Why did you come across two knives?
왜 칼 두 개를 만났나요?
Aren't I worried?
걱정되지 않나요?
I just wanted to find a restaurant to have a drink or two.
그냥 한두 잔 정도 마실 수 있는 식당을 찾고 싶었어요.
As a result, I saw two knives coming in.
그 결과 칼 두 개가 들어오는 것을 보았습니다.
I'm sitting in the corner
나는 구석에 앉아있다
Two knives didn't see me
칼 두 개는 나를 보지 못했어요
Then I looked at the two knives
그 다음 나는 두 개의 칼을 보았습니다.
After having a few drinks
몇 잔 마시고 나면
Just start talking about the train
기차 이야기를 시작해 보세요.
And bragging to that guy?
그리고 그 사람한테 자랑하는 거야?
How about telling him how he is?
그 사람이 어떤지 말해주는 게 어때요?
Helped Zhao An get a batch of cotton yarn
Zhao An이 면사를 구하는 것을 도왔습니다.
The batch he was talking about
그가 말한 배치
Is this our batch of goods?
이게 우리 상품인가요?
Yep
네
because he said
그가 말했으니까
This batch of cotton yarn belongs to Zhao An’s mortal enemy.
이 면사는 조안의 숙적인 적의 것입니다.
Isn't that you?
당신이 아닌가요?
He also said
그는 또한 말했다
What should Zhao An do to reward him heavily?
조안이 그에게 큰 보상을 하려면 어떻게 해야 합니까?
How did Zhao An know?
자오안은 어떻게 알았나요?
how do you know
어떻게 알아?
Should I go to the black market to inquire?
암시장에 가서 문의해야 할까요?
Then Zhao An found out
그러다 자오안(Zhao An)이 알게 됐다.
He guessed it was your cotton yarn
그는 그것이 당신의 면사인줄 알았습니다
are you a pig
너 돼지야?
you are a pig
너는 돼지야
Pig?
돼지?
broken
고장난
Have you never thought about it?
그것에 대해 생각해 본 적이 없나요?
Could it be that someone wanted to frame Chen Jiaping first?
누군가 Chen Jiaping을 먼저 모함하고 싶었을까요?
Drag you into the water again
널 다시 물 속으로 끌고 들어가
broken
고장난
Why are you making so much noise?
왜 그렇게 시끄럽게 굴어요?
In the middle of the night
한밤중에
Come, come, come
어떻게, 어떻게, 어떻게
What's wrong
뭐가 문제 야
Why was my goods robbed again?
왜 내 물건을 또 도둑맞았나요?
Why was it Zhao An who robbed the goods?
물건을 훔친 것은 왜 조안이었는가?
Are you following him again?
너 또 그 사람 따라가는 거야?
Something happened
무슨 일이 일어났어요
What does this have to do with me
이게 나와 무슨 상관이 있는 걸까
Why don't you sleep
왜 안 자?
I'll go to bed first
나 먼저 자러 갈게
let me go
나를 보내줘
you crazy
너 미쳤어
Lao Luo, you want to hit me again
라오루오, 나를 또 때리려 하는구나
Yes or no
예 혹은 아니오
no
아니요
Chen Jiaping is not here
Chen Jiaping은 여기에 없습니다
No one bought rice paper for me
나한테 라이스페이퍼를 사준 사람은 아무도 없어
Are you talking about Chen Jiaping?
천자핑(Chen Jiaping)을 말하는 걸까요?
Is it the five of hearts?
하트 5개인가요?
Is it not important anymore?
더 이상 중요하지 않은가요?
Chen Jiaping needs someone to take responsibility for his crime
Chen Jiaping은 자신의 범죄에 대해 책임을 질 사람이 필요합니다
take the blame
책임을지다
That
저것
Who can I turn to take the blame?
누구에게 책임을 물을 수 있습니까?
What do you think?
어떻게 생각하나요?
Where did Jiang Zhaoguo's labor certificate leak out?
장자오궈 노동증명서는 어디에서 유출됐나?
Zhao An
자오안
Do you mean to let Zhao An
자오안(Zhao An)에게 허락하시겠습니까?
No way
안 돼요
That
저것
It is impossible for the Japanese to believe
일본인은 믿을 수 없다.
Zhao An is the five of hearts.
조안(趙灯)은 다섯 마음이다.
Japanese people don't believe it
일본사람들은 안믿어요
Just try to make him believe it
그 사람이 그것을 믿게 만들려고 노력해보세요
No matter whether Chen Jiaping is the Five of Hearts or not,
Chen Jiaping이 Five of Hearts인지 여부에 관계없이
Can't trust him anymore
더 이상 그 사람을 믿을 수 없어요
Since you don't trust him anymore
당신이 그 사람을 더 이상 믿지 않으니까
Then why are you trying your best to save him?
그런데 왜 그를 구하기 위해 최선을 다하는 거죠?
You thought I was saving him
넌 내가 그 사람을 구한다고 생각했지
I'm saving myself
나는 나 자신을 구하고 있다
This time I'm fighting against the city
이번에는 도시와 싸우고 있어요
Zhao An and I
자오안과 나
Not a fish that dies
죽는 물고기가 아니다
It’s just that the network is broken
그냥 네트워크가 끊어진 것 뿐이야
That
저것
any idea
어떤 생각이라도
Can Zhao An become the Five of Hearts?
조안은 다섯 마음이 될 수 있을까?
Manager Luo
루오 매니저
Do you already have a clever idea?
이미 기발한 아이디어가 있나요?
I talked to Tongji Company in Chongqing
충칭에 있는 Tongji Company와 이야기를 나눴습니다.
Already discussed
이미 논의됨
After Jia Ping was sent to the military police headquarters
자평이 헌병사령부로 보내진 후
Naoki Uchida interrogated him personally
우치다 나오키가 직접 그를 심문했다.
Jia Ping said firmly
Jia Ping이 단호하게 말했습니다.
It's because of Jiang Zhaoguo
장자오궈 때문이다
Misunderstood his relationship with Han Lu
한루와의 관계를 오해했다
It was out of jealousy that I deliberately framed him
질투심에 일부러 모함한거였어
But the Japanese
그러나 일본인은
I don't believe this statement at all
나는 이 말을 전혀 믿지 않는다.
But apart from Jiang Zhaoguo’s confession
하지만 장자오궈의 고백과는 별도로
There is no other evidence
다른 증거는 없습니다
I heard
나는 들었다
It was Luo Guanqun who begged for Jiaping's love
가평에게 사랑을 구걸한 사람은 나관춘이었다.
The Japanese did not execute him
일본인은 그를 처형하지 않았다
Later, he was transferred to a detention center
이후 구치소로 이송됐다.
detention center
구치소
In fact, it is the prison of the Military Police Headquarters.
사실 헌병사령부의 감옥이다.
Just not far from Huasheng Road
Huasheng Road에서 멀지 않은 곳에 있습니다.
So where is Jiang Zhaoguo now?
그렇다면 장자오궈는 지금 어디에 있는가?
Jiang Zhaoguo was placed under house arrest in
장자오궈(江趙國)가 가택연금됐다.
The internal guest house of the Gendarmerie Headquarters
헌병사령부 내부 게스트하우스
The Japanese want to instigate him
일본인은 그를 선동하고 싶어한다
Thank you
감사합니다
Help me find out so much news
많은 소식을 알 수 있도록 도와주세요
You must have taken a lot of risks.
당신은 많은 위험을 감수했을 것입니다.
nothing
아무것도 아님
I am mainly responsible for organizing files
나는 주로 파일 정리를 담당한다.
Access various departments
다양한 부서에 접근
It is not easy to arouse suspicion
의혹을 불러일으키기 쉽지 않다
double peach
더블 복숭아
Is there any way you can save Jia Ping?
Jia Ping을 구할 수 있는 방법이 있나요?
I'm still thinking of a way
아직 방법을 생각 중이에요
Come and wash my feet
와서 내 발을 씻어 주시오
newcomer
새로 온 사람
Today it's your turn to wash the boss's feet
오늘은 당신이 사장님의 발을 씻어줄 차례입니다
past
과거
Letting you wash your feet is to give you face
발을 씻게 하는 것은 얼굴을 주는 것이요
Beat you and me to death
너와 나를 때려 죽여라
Brat
애새끼
I'm done with it, I'm done with it
난 끝났어, 난 끝났어
Take, take, take
받아, 가져, 가져
You just deserve a beating
넌 정말 구타당할 자격이 있어
Wash my feet quickly
발 빨리 씻어
wash wash wash
빨래 빨래
hurry up
서둘러요
I'm coming
나는 간다
Come
오다
Big brother
형
Is it comfortable?
편안합니까?
That's pretty much it
그 정도예요
I tell you
나는 당신에게 말한다
I only wash my wife’s feet, do you understand?
나는 아내의 발만 씻는다. 알겠는가?
Chen Jiaping
첸 지아핑
How many times have you caused trouble?
몇 번이나 문제를 일으켰나요?
three times
세 번
A few days after arriving
도착하고 며칠 후
We've had trouble three times.
우리는 세 번이나 어려움을 겪었습니다.
Are you seeking death?
당신은 죽음을 추구하고 있습니까?
sir
선생님
I was wronged
나는 부당한 대우를 받았다
Everyone here says they are wronged
여기 있는 사람들은 다 자기들이 잘못됐다고 말해요
starting today
오늘부터
I'll transfer you to cell 206
206호실로 연결해 드릴게요
Pack your things and follow me
짐을 싸고 나를 따라오세요
hurry up
서둘러요
How did you do that face?
그 얼굴은 어떻게 한 거야?
Fighting by Luo Guanqun
Luo Guanqun의 싸움
can you take me away right away
나를 지금 당장 데려갈 수 있나요
I never want to be with that devil again
난 다시는 그 악마랑 같이 있고 싶지 않아
Luo Guanqun
루오관쿤
so
그래서
You go to Pudong to stay for a while first
넌 먼저 푸동에 잠시 머물러 가
What is temporary residence?
임시거주란 무엇입니까?
Don’t you want to be with me forever?
나랑 영원히 같이 있고 싶지 않아?
together forever
영원히 함께
Soon, soon
곧 곧
I don't want to hear it anymore
더 이상 듣고 싶지 않아요
I've heard it many times
여러번 들어봤어
You lied to me
당신은 나에게 거짓말을 했어요
I'm Zhao An
저는 자오안이에요
Even if you lie to everyone in the world
세상 모든 사람에게 거짓말을 해도
I won't even lie to you Zhang Shuyun
난 너한테 거짓말도 안 할게 장수윤
That
저것
When will you send me to Pudong?
나를 언제 푸둥으로 보내시겠어요?
Tomorrow night at nine o'clock
내일 밤 아홉시
Wait for me at Huangpu River Ferry No. 7
황포강 페리 7번에서 기다려주세요
remember
기억하다
Don't let Luo Guanqun arouse suspicion
Luo Guanqun이 의심을 불러일으키지 않도록 하세요.
Pack your things quickly
빨리 짐을 싸세요
go ahead
어서
Enter
입력하다
how's it going
어떻게되고 있습니까
seen
본
His name is Hou Si
이름이 허우시인 사람
He's a smuggler
그 사람은 밀수업자예요
how could he know
그 사람이 어떻게 알겠어요?
I have cotton yarn on my hand
손에 면실이 있어요
I found someone to spread the word on the black market.
암시장에 소문을 퍼뜨릴 사람을 찾았어요.
He followed this clue to find me
그는 나를 찾기 위해 이 단서를 따라갔다
How much does he give
그 사람은 얼마를 주나요?
One hundred yuan a pack
한팩에 100위안
A pack costs more than 70 yuan on the black market.
암시장에서 한 팩의 가격은 70위안 이상입니다.
He gave one hundred yuan
그는 100위안을 주었다
He knows my background
그 사람은 내 배경을 알고 있어
Won't lie to me
나한테는 거짓말 안 할 거야
Fourteen hundred bales of cotton yarn
면사 1400가마니
That is
그건
140,000 yuan
140,000위안
But Hou Si said
그런데 허시가 말했다.
Such a large quantity of goods
이렇게 많은 양의 상품이
He can't transport it out of Shanghai
그는 그것을 상하이 밖으로 운반할 수 없다
We need to figure it out ourselves
우리 스스로 알아내야 해
He was meeting outside the city
그는 도시 밖에서 만나고 있었다
You need to use your brain too.
두뇌도 사용해야 합니다.
Very easy to handle
취급이 매우 용이함
Just Japanese
그냥 일본인
Let's transport opium to the Kuomintang-controlled areas
국민당 통제지역으로 아편을 수송하자
We have a pass to leave the city
우리는 도시를 떠날 수 있는 패스를 가지고 있습니다
Chen Jiaping
첸 지아핑
I tell you
나는 당신에게 말한다
There is a madman living in 206
206에는 미친 사람이 살고 있어요
The three people who lived with him
그와 함께 살았던 세 사람
One had his eyeballs gouged out
한 명은 눈알이 뽑혔어
One had his ear bitten off
한 명은 귀가 잘렸어요
Where is the other one?
다른 하나는 어디에 있습니까?
The whole hand was bitten off
손 전체가 물렸어요
go ahead
어서
Wang Dapu
왕다푸
He is Chen Jiaping
그는 천자핑(Chen Jiaping)이다.
He will live with you from now on
그 사람은 이제부터 너랑 같이 살 거야.
You should be nicer to him
그 사람에게 좀 더 친절해져야 해
Welcome
환영
My name is Wang Dapu
내 이름은 왕다푸예요
Chen Jiaping
첸 지아핑
What do you think of this movie?
이 영화에 대해 어떻게 생각하세요?
The plot is boring
줄거리가 지루하다
slow pace
느린 속도
Acting artificial
인공적으로 행동하다
Who would spend money to watch this kind of crappy movie?
누가 이런 엉뚱한 영화를 보기 위해 돈을 쓰겠습니까?
that is
그건
No wonder today’s movie tickets
오늘 영화표도 이상하지 않아?
Not only is it free
무료일 뿐만 아니라
And as long as you enter the theater
그리고 극장에 입장하자마자
Not leaving the table midway
테이블을 중간에 떠나지 않음
You can still get a dollar for nothing
당신은 여전히 ​​​​아무것도없이 1 달러를 얻을 수 있습니다
This is a completely bad movie
이거 완전 나쁜 영화야
I'm coming here
나는 여기로 온다
Just came here for Du Fei
Du Fei를 위해 방금 여기에 왔습니다
But he was only out for a minute
하지만 그 사람은 밖에 잠시 밖에 없었어
from beginning to end
처음부터 끝까지
I just looked at Han Lu’s face
방금 한루 얼굴 봤는데
dangling on the screen
화면에 매달려
It's so annoying
너무 짜증나
What do you think Han Lu is capable of?
한루의 능력이 무엇이라고 생각하시나요?
So many popular stars have matched her
그녀와 어울리는 인기 스타가 너무 많아
Behind this
이 뒤에
There must be a big boss who is favoring her.
그녀를 편애하는 큰 상사가 있을 것이다.
Yeah
응
I just heard the person sitting next to me say
방금 내 옆에 앉은 사람이 말하는 것을 들었습니다.
This movie theater today
오늘 이 영화관
Almost no one comes in with a ticket.
티켓을 가지고 오는 사람은 거의 없습니다.
real
진짜
Ninety percent
90%
They are all here to act as trustees like us.
그들은 모두 우리와 같은 수탁자 역할을 하기 위해 여기에 있습니다.
I guess
내 생각엔
This is what the big boss spent
사장님이 이렇게 쓰셨어요
Just to make Hanlu happy
한루를 행복하게 해주기 위해서
you do not say
당신은 말하지 않는다
let's go
갑시다
Hurry up and get the money
빨리 돈 받아와
It's too late anymore
이젠 너무 늦었어
OK OK OK
오케이 오케이 오케이
wait for me wait for me wait for me
기다려주세요 기다려주세요 기다려주세요
Many people came to today's press conference
오늘 기자간담회에는 많은 분들이 오셨습니다
Very grand
아주 웅장하다
I
나
I don't want to go
나는 가고 싶지 않다
I came here just to tell you
나는 단지 당신에게 말하려고 여기에 왔습니다
I'm a little tired
나는 조금 피곤해
Want to go back and rest
돌아가서 쉬고 싶다
Miss Hanlu
미스 한루
Today's press conference
오늘 기자회견
You'd better show up
당신이 나타나는 것이 좋습니다
Because I have something very important
나에겐 아주 중요한 일이 있기 때문에
To be announced in front of all reporters
모든 기자들 앞에서 발표됩니다.
Something about you and me
당신과 나에 대한 뭔가
whats the matter
무슨 일이야
I want to do it in front of all the reporters
기자들 앞에서 하고 싶다
propose to you
당신에게 프로포즈하다
my sincerity towards you
당신을 향한 나의 진심
I think you know
내 생각엔 당신도 알고 있는 것 같아요
No
아니요
Mr. Yamashita
Mr. Yamashita
sorry
죄송합니다
I
나
Miss Hanlu
미스 한루
I don't like forcing you
너한테 강요하는 건 싫어
Is this good?
이게 좋은가요?
Think about it first
먼저 생각해보세요
And me
그리고 나
Go deal with the reporters
가서 기자들과 거래해
I'll wait for you to come over
당신이 오기를 기다릴게요
Miss Hanlu
미스 한루
Did you know that Jiang Zhaoguo was arrested?
장자오궈(Jiang Zhaoguo)가 체포되었다는 사실을 알고 계셨나요?
What did you say
뭐라고 하셨나요
I think you've guessed it
짐작하신 것 같아요
Mr. Yamashita is not an ordinary businessman
야마시타 씨는 평범한 사업가가 아닙니다
He is working for the Japanese Empire
그는 일본제국을 위해 일하고 있다
do something great
뭔가 대단한 일을 해라
He is a very powerful man
그는 매우 강력한 사람이다
As long as Miss Hanlu is willing to marry Mr. Yamashita
한루양이 야마시타씨와 결혼할 의사가 있는 한
he can do anything for you
그 사람은 널 위해서라면 뭐든지 할 수 있어
Miss Hanlu
미스 한루
only you now
지금은 너뿐이야
Only then can Jiang Zhaoguo's life be saved.
그래야만 장자오궈의 생명을 구할 수 있다.
you can think about it
당신은 그것에 대해 생각할 수 있습니다
But time is running out
하지만 시간이 부족해
Mr. Yamashita and the reporters are still waiting.
야마시타 씨와 기자들은 아직도 기다리고 있습니다.
I'll ask you one last time
마지막으로 하나만 묻겠습니다
Do you have anything else to say?
다른 할 말씀 있으신가요?
I already told you the identity of the five of hearts.
다섯 마음의 정체에 대해서는 이미 말씀드렸습니다.
you know very well
당신은 아주 잘 알고
we want more than that
우리는 그 이상을 원해요
What is your mission in Shanghai?
상하이에서 당신의 임무는 무엇입니까?
Why are you so interested in the CCP’s side currency?
중국 공산당의 부통화에 왜 그토록 관심이 있습니까?
good
좋은
I said
나는 말했다
Boss Dai
보스 다이
Arranged two agents
에이전트 2명 배치
The financial system lurking in the CCP’s border areas
중국 공산당 국경 지역에 숨어 있는 금융 시스템
The codenames are Magpie and Dayan.
코드네임은 Magpie와 Dayan이다.
before their identities are revealed
그들의 정체가 밝혀지기 전에
They've got the recipe for edge paper
그들은 가장자리 종이를 만드는 방법을 가지고 있어요
Hebian coin copper plate
허비안 동전 동판
Then they fled Yan'an
그런 다음 그들은 Yan'an을 떠났습니다.
I come to Shanghai this time
이번에 상해에 왔어요
Just to meet them
단지 그들을 만나기 위해서
Bring these two things back to Chongqing
이 두 가지를 충칭으로 가져오세요
What do you want these things for?
무엇 때문에 이런 것들을 원하시나요?
The Chongqing government has launched a
충칭 정부는
Counterfeiting border currency to destroy the CCP’s border economy
중국 공산당의 국경 경제를 파괴하기 위해 국경 화폐 위조
secret plan
비계
Magpie is the person I want to meet at the Majestic Hotel
까치는 마제스틱 호텔에서 만나고 싶은 사람이에요
I was followed by your people at that time
그때 네 사람들이 따라왔어
So we didn't meet
그래서 우리는 안 만났어요
later
나중에
He died mysteriously
의문의 죽음을 맞이했습니다
I didn't get the recipe for edge paper either.
Edge Paper의 레시피도 얻지 못했습니다.
What about the wild geese?
기러기는 어떻습니까?
The wild goose is missing
기러기가 빠졌네요
Haven't been able to contact him
그 사람한테 연락이 안 됐어요.
Help
돕다
Sir, help me
선생님, 도와주세요
What's wrong
뭐가 문제 야
sir sir
선생님
Help, help, help
도와주세요, 도와주세요, 도와주세요
He wants to cut my nose
그 사람이 내 코를 자르고 싶어해
my nose is gone
내 코가 없어졌어
If you guessed correctly
올바르게 추측했다면
Do you want to jailbreak?
탈옥하시겠습니까?
I don't understand what you mean
무슨 말인지 이해가 안 돼요
You made a total of six keys
총 6개의 열쇠를 만들었어요
cell key
셀 키
corridor key
복도 열쇠
There are also keys to each stairwell.
각 계단통에는 열쇠도 있습니다.
Right
오른쪽
I said why are you poking out people's eyes?
왜 사람들의 눈을 찌르고 있습니까?
Biting someone's ear?
누군가의 귀를 물고 있습니까?
I just don’t want anyone to live with you
난 그냥 누구도 너랑 같이 사는 걸 원하지 않아
I'll delay you in making the key.
열쇠 만드는 시간을 늦추겠습니다.
I'm curious
궁금해
How did you guess it?
어떻게 추측하셨나요?
you tell me first
네가 먼저 말해봐
how did you do it
넌 어떻게 그걸 했니
What do you think
어떻게 생각하나요
By observing
관찰함으로써
The key in the Japanese soldier's waist
일본군 허리에 있던 열쇠
Remember the shape of each key
각 키의 모양을 기억하세요
Then draw it
그럼 그려봐
Follow the picture
그림을 따라가세요
Make the key again
열쇠를 다시 만드세요
Where is this key material?
이 핵심 자료는 어디에 있나요?
It should be the metal hinge on this bed.
이 침대의 금속 경첩이겠죠.
I said my bed
나는 내 침대를 말했다
live shaky
불안하게 살아
This is also another
이것도 또 다른데
you don't want to be with anyone else
당신은 다른 사람과 함께 있고 싶지 않아요
Maybe the reason for living together?
어쩌면 함께 사는 이유가 아닐까?
You are smarter than the previous few
당신은 이전 몇 명보다 더 똑똑합니다
But one person is too smart
그런데 한 사람이 너무 똑똑해요.
Not necessarily a good thing
반드시 좋은 것은 아니다
All they might lose are their eyes and ears
그들이 잃을 수 있는 것은 눈과 귀뿐이다
And you
당신은요
What is lost may be life
잃어버린 것은 생명일지도 모른다
No more keys
더 이상 열쇠가 없습니다
Where is the key
열쇠는 어디에 있습니까?
Look for it
찾아보다
I've never left this house
난 이 집에서 한 번도 나가본 적이 없어
The key is still in the house
열쇠는 아직 집에 있어요
give me the key
나에게 열쇠를 줘
put the knife down
칼을 내려놔
what on earth do you want
도대체 뭘 원하는 거야?
I didn't think about it
나는 그것에 대해 생각하지 않았다
I just think when I go out
그냥 나갈때 생각나
Don't miss an eye
눈 하나도 놓치지 마세요
missing ears
귀가 없어진
Scare my wife again
아내에게 또 겁을 주다
give me the key
나에게 열쇠를 줘
I can't move you
나는 당신을 움직일 수 없습니다
Why should I believe you?
내가 왜 당신을 믿어야합니까?
How do you agree to give me the key?
나에게 열쇠를 주는 데 어떻게 동의하나요?
Wait until I get out
내가 나갈 때까지 기다려
I'll give you the key when I get out
나갈 때 열쇠를 줄게
no
아니요
I don't have enough time
시간이 부족해요
I have to escape tomorrow
내일 탈출해야 해
Why does it have to be tomorrow?
왜 꼭 내일이어야 합니까?
There's a sympathy show tomorrow night
내일 밤에 애도 쇼가 있어요
that time
그때
The Japanese had the weakest defense
일본군은 방어력이 가장 약했다
That's the best time
그때가 가장 좋은 때야
Then you might not be able to get out
그러면 아마 못 나갈 수도 있겠지
It's not time for me to leave yet
아직은 떠날 시간이 아니야
give me the key
나에게 열쇠를 줘
I'll take you to escape with me
당신을 데리고 탈출에 나설게요
I'll escape with you
너와 함께 탈출할게
Are you kidding me?
농담하는 거야?
How could I go out with you?
내가 어떻게 너랑 데이트할 수 있겠어?
I was brought here unjustly
나는 부당하게 여기로 끌려왔어
After the investigation, I can release you.
조사가 끝나면 석방해 드리겠습니다.
I'll run out with you
난 너와 함께 달려갈 거야
I can't explain it even more clearly.
나는 그것을 더 명확하게 설명할 수 없다.
this place
여기
I stayed longer than you
내가 너보다 오래 머물렀어
I've only seen people coming in
사람들이 들어오는 걸 본 적이 있어요
I've never seen anyone go out before
난 지금까지 밖에 나가는 사람을 본 적이 없어